What's with that getup?
The nursery's going on a field trip to pick sweet potatoes!
Where'd you see that?
It was in a magazine I saw at the convenience store.
The Future of Farming
All the field workers were dressed like this!
Are you picking potatoes or catching bugs!?
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
... Searching at Sunset.
Thanks for having us again this year.
No problem.
Pick as many as you like.
Thank you.
You've gotta carry everything you pick back yourself, okay?
Promise me you'll only pick as much as you can carry.
Look, Kobato! They're connected!
This one's huge!
They really are! Now I want to try too!
Oww...
It's so big!
Wow!
Dobato!
Kobato, you're all dirty.
Huh?
Who's that?
He's a little older than anyone from Yomogi...
Maybe he's from this farm?
No, her grandchildren are already in high school.
Then...
Who is he?
Hey.
You alone?
You live around here?
Hold it!
Sorry it took us so long to realize.
Don't worry, it happens.
Was he from the neighborhood?
All right, let's clean up and head back.
Okay!
You picked so many!
Kobato!
Look at them all!
I tried my best!
Hey.
Didn't I tell you?
You've gotta carry everything you pick.
All right, we're roasting them when we get back.
You gonna be okay, Kobato?
Can we help?
I'm fine! I'll carry them myself!
You can't do it. Let us help.
No! I promised I'd do it myself!
Of course you will.
You're such a meanie.
You can't do it. Give up, Kobato.
Young lady!
Let me lend a hand.
Really?
Thank you.
Are they done yet?
It's smoky!
They're hot!
Here.
Thanks!
Be careful, okay? It's hot.
Hey!
There you go.
What do we do with these?
Shall we cook more?
Let's share them with the neighborhood.
Fujimoto, take Kobato along with you.
I'd rather go alone. It'll be quicker.
No, you should go together.
I want her to get to know the neighbors better.
Okay, Kobato?
Sure!
I'll try my best!
I won't make you help. Just stay out of my way.
But they're my sweet potatoes!
He's such a meanie. Always telling me to stay out of the way.
But he didn't tell you not to follow him.
But he took my sweet potatoes! I was hoping for leftovers!
Aren't they heavy? It's more like he's carrying them for you.
Hello?
We're from Yomogi Nursery.
We went picking tasty sweet potatoes, and now we have plenty to share!
Oh my. Thank you!
We're from Yomogi Nursery!
Thanks.
Have some sweet potatoes!
Thanks a lot.
We're from Yomogi Nursery!
Fujimoto...
We're almost done!
Oh my.
Welcome back.
Hello!
Oh, it's you! It's been a while.
Yeah!
How have you been doing, Milk?
You've gotten bigger.
Yeah, she has.
She's been doing well.
That's him.
Oh, him. He came by and asked for some water.
He said he'd picked some sweet potatoes.
Hey, you!
You're that kid!
Hey, hold it!
I said, hold it!
Let me go, you thief!
That's my line, you potato thief!
Put me down!
Fujimoto! What are you doing?
I'm bringing this thief to the police.
No way! Lemme go!
I knew it.
You're a runaway.
A runaway?
What's your name?
What, keeping quiet?
Just call him "potato thief".
I'm not a potato thief!
You have a name, don't you?
Keita.
Why did you run away from home, Keita?
I wanted to go to my old house.
Your old home?
The house I used to live at.
Mom got a new job, so we had to move.
So did you go yet?
Not yet.
Are you going now?
Well, I want to, but...
You forgot where it is, right?
I didn't forget!
You sure look like you did.
Wrong!
You wouldn't forget where your home is, would you?
I just haven't been there since kindergarten...
I can't quite remember.
That means you forgot.
I haven't forgotten!
Keita!
If we don't know what kind of house it is, we can't help you look.
Can you draw it for us?
Sure I can!
Well, umm...
It had a red roof, and windows here and here.
There was an antenna here, and...
Why don't you draw things that were nearby, too?
That'll make it easier to look.
There was a mailbox here, and a dog lived next door.
That's a big dog.
He always barked when I walked by.
Yoshimura Keita
Oh, and Mom was always baking something.
She read to me, and on days off we went to the park or camping.
Keita?
I wanna go back to my old home.
Fujimoto.
I'm gonna help Keita find his home.
It'll be tough to find just looking for a dog and a mailbox.
Can't you remember anything else?
Which way? Right or left?
Um... Over here!
No, here!
I know where I am now!
I've been here!
I see. We must be getting close.
Aren't you happy, Keita?
Are you thirsty?
I have to be thrifty!
Thrifty?
That's a big word for someone your age.
Mom says it all the time.
Over here.
Fujimoto?
Free
That's...
Pears, can't you tell?
Here.
Should I?
I'll leave these.
This is tasty.
See, he's not all bad.
Of course not.
Hey, give me a pear too!
Maybe it's this dog.
That means...
It's gotta be around here.
This isn't my house.
Yoshimura
Let's go in.
Move.
My room...
It's locked.
Looks like we have to bust in.
Fujimoto!
Please!
Don't break it!
Don't you want to go back home?
Grandpa's there.
Grandpa?
Mom and I live at Grandpa's now.
Keita, do you hate your grandpa?
He's so mean!
Mean?
He's...
He always bugs me to get up in the morning.
Come on, Keita! Get up!
Make your bed!
I want to stay up later watching TV and playing games.
Keita!
What are you doing, Grandpa!?
Stop hanging around and go to sleep!
At meals, he always wants me to eat things I hate.
Things you hate?
Like veggies and fish.
Keita!
Stop playing with your food!
Eat it!
Is he really being mean?
Yeah! He hates me!
He's always scolding me!
I'd rather run away!
So I don't wanna...
Keita...
Miss Sayaka always tells the kids at the nursery to eat their fish and veggies because they're nutritious.
Who's Miss Sayaka?
She's the teacher at Yomogi Nursery. She's kind and loves kids.
Kind?
Keita!
You should go to bed after you bathe!
Is he really mean?
It's hard to tell.
But I'm sure if we take a closer look, we'll figure it out.
Keita, were you going to roast sweet potatoes here?
We used to all do it together here. They were tasty.
You should man up and bring these home with you.
I already apologized to the farmer.
She dug up so many that we have leftovers.
See, Keita, it all worked out.
Yeah.
Can you make it back alone?
I told you I'd be fine!
Keita!
Grandpa!
Here.
Keita!
Grandpa!
Ow!
That hurt!
What the hell are you doing, old man?
Quit making me worried, you brat!
Let's go home.
Your mom's waiting.
Okay.
Keita met his grandpa, and they're getting on the train now.
No problem. Later.
Fujimoto, you knew Keita's phone number?
Did you call his grandpa?
Maybe.
Anyway, I'm hungry.
Let's go home and steam these potatoes.
Um...
Okay.
What now?
It's nothing.
Hey.
Oh, Domoto!
You heading home?
I've got something to do, so I'm going straight back.
Something to do?
The nursery went sweet potato picking today.
Then we gave out the extras to the neighbors.
Fujimoto's really a nice guy, isn't he.
Yeah, Kiyokazu's a nice guy.
This must be from that brat.
He seemed sad seeing his old house.
Must be because he found out how his grandpa really felt.
I see.
Anyway, Fujimoto tried hard today.
You each did half, so 50 points!
But he was a meanie all morning!
Yeah, you're right.
That puts him at zero.
Kobato, you tried hard, so 70 points!
Can't you erase the other one?
You sure do love to complain.
I was right, you did half so your get 50 points.
Come on, erase it!
Shut up! 25 points!
What, aren't you happy yet? 12.5 points!
My face is covered in ink...
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Secret Wish.
Next episode